# Peter Sekan UX & frontend engineer



My name is Pete, and I am a UX & frontend engineer with a strong focus on implementing and maintaining design systems and frontend component libraries. With over a decade of experience in software design covering different roles, I am able to design and build great user interfaces, create and develop awesome teams, implement and improve processes that speed up the production cycle, and still make it feel fun!

# Education

# Certified Full Stack Developer Ironhack Web Dev Bootcamp February 2023 - May 2023

During this nine-week long course, we have built See two of my projects: three web projects, from a static HTML page to a fully functional web application with ReactJS, ExpressJS, and MongoDB.

The Cyrano Service NoGame

# Bachelor of Arts in Interface Design University of Applied Science Potsdam

August 2007 - May 2014

During my studies I have focused on the following topics: human-computer interaction, usability, design by numbers, physical computing, typography, typeface design, art and design theory. In most cases, I have chosen coding as my tool for creation.

See some of my projects: Redesign Design Radar Processing 2.0 Font Fun Friday

#### Contact

Karl-Kunger-Straße 5 D-12435 Berlin

sekan.pete@gmail.com petersekan.de

GitHub LinkedIn

### **Soft Skills**

Learner, harmonist, inputer, active listener, maximizer, individualizationist, mediator (INFP), team player, creative.

### **UX Skills**

Design thinking, UI design, atomic design, whiteboard, documentation, workshops, typography, icon design, brand design.

## **Engineering Skills**

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Git, ReactJS, MongoDB, ExpressJS, Vite, Svelte, AnimeJS, Markdown, NPM, TailwindCSS, Sass.

### Software Skills

VS Code, Sketch, Figma, Jira, Trello, Miro, Notion, AdobeCC, Glyphs, MS Office, Google Docs.

# Peter Sekan UX & frontend engineer

# **Work Experience**

# Associate Director Product Design at Marketlogic Software

January 2019 - June 2022

I was responsible for hiring, developing, and mentoring a team of UX professionals. Together with this team, we have brought the Marketlogic Software platform from the browser to mobile devices, with a unified design system.

#### Responsibilities:

Team developement, design system, ux design, documentation, task management.

# Design Engineer at Marketlogic Software

June 2016 - December 2018

I have improved the communication between designers and engineers by building a living style guide and prototypes with ReactJS and a Sketch component library. Which has lead to the implementation of the company's first design system.

### Responsibilities:

Design system, prototyping, component library, UX & UI design, documentation.

# Freelance Interface Designer

July 2011 - June 2016

As a freelancer, I have provided visual designs for websites and layouts, but also provided full-stack solutions for websites.

Still living project: Praxis Lars Werner

### Contact

Karl-Kunger-Straße 5 D-12435 Berlin

sekan.pete@gmail.com petersekan.de

<u>GitHub</u> LinkedIn

### Languages

Professional English & native German.

### **Professional Skills**

Team building & developing, mentoring, Agile, Scrum, task management, presentation.

#### **Personal Skills**

Caring dad, good friend, great cook.